<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Codurance</title>
    <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href=""/>
    <updated>2016-08-17T17:10:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://codurance.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Codurance</name>
        <email>hello@codurance.com</email>
    </author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) Codurance</rights>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2016/08/03/testing-spark-streaming-integration-testing-with-docker-compose/</id>
        <title>Testing Spark Streaming: Integration testing with Docker Compose</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/2016/08/03/testing-spark-streaming-integration-testing-with-docker-compose/"/>
        <published>2016-08-03T00:20:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://codurance.com/2016/08/02/testing-spark-streaming-unit-testing/&quot;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; of this series, we saw how to unit test &lt;a href=&quot;http://spark.apache.org/streaming/&quot;&gt;Spark Streaming&lt;/a&gt; operations using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/holdenk/spark-testing-base&quot;&gt;Spark Testing Base&lt;/a&gt;. Here we&#39;ll see how to do integration testing using &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/compose/&quot;&gt;Docker Compose&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2016/08/02/what-does-RESTful-really-mean/</id>
        <title>What does RESTful really mean</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/2016/08/02/what-does-RESTful-really-mean/"/>
        <published>2016-08-02T17:00:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month I attended &lt;a href=&quot;https://skillsmatter.com/courses/541-fast-track-to-restful-to-microservices&quot;&gt;Fast Track to RESTful Microservices training&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://skillsmatter.com&quot;&gt;Skillsmatter&lt;/a&gt;. During the course, we explored what REST APIs can offer to web applications in general and microservices communication in particular. Personally, the most important outcome of the course is a better understanding of what REST really means and what are its pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2016/08/02/testing-spark-streaming-unit-testing/</id>
        <title>Testing Spark Streaming: Unit testing</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/2016/08/02/testing-spark-streaming-unit-testing/"/>
        <published>2016-08-02T00:20:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is enough evidence to prove the importance of automated testing. Projects in new fields often neglect automated testing, as the domain itself steals the attention of the developers. However, lack of testing implies &#39;laugh now, cry later&#39;. Some of the tools around Big Data space have been architected around testability or, at least, the community has taken care of it afterwards. We&#39;ll see how &lt;a href=&quot;http://spark.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Spark&lt;/a&gt;, and more specifically &lt;a href=&quot;http://spark.apache.org/streaming/&quot;&gt;Spark Streaming&lt;/a&gt;, performs in different aspects of automated testing.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/software-creation/2016/07/25/thoughts-on-coupling-in-software-design/</id>
        <title>Thoughts on Coupling in Software Design</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/software-creation/2016/07/25/thoughts-on-coupling-in-software-design/"/>
        <published>2016-07-25T10:00:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Coupling is a software metric that describes how closely connected two routines or modules are. It is a measure of quality. The concept was introduced by Larry Constantine in the 1960s and was formulized in a 1974 article for the IBM Systems Journal, Structured Design, and in the 1979 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.win.tue.nl/~wstomv/quotes/structured-design.html&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; by the same name.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/technology/2016/07/15/scaling-umbraco-on-windows-azure/</id>
        <title>Scaling Umbraco On Windows Azure Part III</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/technology/2016/07/15/scaling-umbraco-on-windows-azure/"/>
        <published>2016-07-15T10:20:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the last part of the series about how to scale an Umbraco website on the Windows Azure platform.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;You’re being successful, cater for more visits&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of platforms as a service like Windows Azure, is that you don’t have to know in advance how many sites your company will have, or how popular and resource consuming your application will be.
The platform provides you a way to &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/blog/scaling-up-and-scaling-out-in-windows-azure-web-sites/&quot;&gt;adapt your hosting&lt;/a&gt; to whatever the needs are at a given time.
In the Windows Azure platform you can scale your sites on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Scaling Up&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Scaling up will allow your application to get more resources on the same instance.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Scaling Out&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Scaling out on Windows Azure consists of spinning additional instances of the application.
Load balancing between the instances is provided by the platform and thus does not require further configuration.
The application must therefore be multi-instance safe. This requires extra care to ensure that items such as how the data is consumed by the application, the handling of user sessions and access to resources are thread safe.
Sticky-sessions are not managed out of the box by the Azure platform, one way to ensure continuity of sessions on multi-instances is to store sessions in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/gg185668.aspx&quot;&gt;Azure session state provider&lt;/a&gt; or in the Azure Redis Cache; another way would be to leverage the &lt;a href=&quot;https://channel9.msdn.com/shows/Cloud+Cover/Cloud-Cover-Episode-24-Routing-in-Windows-Azure/&quot;&gt;routing capabilities in Windows Azure&lt;/a&gt; to route requests to stateful instances.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Go to the application settings on your Windows Azure Web Service (WAWS) platform and look for the App service plan menu. There you will find the Scale out menu.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/20.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately scaling functionality is not part of the Free Service Plan.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/21.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;So we need to select the S1 Standard plan to be able to access scaling options and configure the scaling of our application. We can see that for the moment we have only one instance running.
We can manually add another instance of our application. Or we can scale given the CPU usage in percentage of our application.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/22.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;I modified the home page template to add some dummy code and get the page to fetch blog posts multiple times, triggering many requests to the server.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/23.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Looking back into the Azure portal, we can see that the scaling took place.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/24.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;And I even received an email letting me know that my application is scaling.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/25.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;After about twenty minutes without activity on the website, and having removed the code that caused extra load on the CPUs, our application has been automatically scaled back down to one instance.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/26.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;In this part of the series, we have showed how to automatically scale an Umbraco installation, without having to worry about anything other than the cost.
However scaling an application requires you to manage the its state at a global level.
For Umbraco for example, the main pain points are handling the session state, the Lucene index files and the config file.
Depending on the version of Umbraco you run, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.orbitone.com/post/Does-Umbraco-really-loves-Windows-Azure&quot;&gt;some of those concerns&lt;/a&gt; have been addressed.
Notice that we did not need any Visual Studio IDE, nor did we need to install IIS, we have a scalable website within a few clicks.
This is the peace of mind that well-built software should give you.
Always remember that a hundred-instance production software system might have different needs than a ten-instance one.
Maybe you need more powerful tools to monitor and inspect the state of your platform.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/videos/2016/07/14/shape-your-infrastructure-with-terraform/</id>
        <title>Shape your infrastructure with Terraform</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/videos/2016/07/14/shape-your-infrastructure-with-terraform/"/>
        <published>2016-07-14T10:59:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Shape your infrastructure with Terraform&lt;/h2&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2016/07/11/state-in-scalable-architectures/</id>
        <title>State in scalable architectures</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/2016/07/11/state-in-scalable-architectures/"/>
        <published>2016-07-11T00:20:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Handling state is one of the cornerstones of software development. Most of business value derived from software relies on state. Depending on the level of abstraction, state, and the approach to handle it, looks like a completely different problem. In this post we&#39;ll see what is common to all of them and how modern scalability needs have pushed towards innovative and refreshing approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/craftsmanship/2016/07/04/the-rush-age/</id>
        <title>The Rush Age</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/craftsmanship/2016/07/04/the-rush-age/"/>
        <published>2016-07-04T10:00:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We live in the rush age. We are literally overwhelmed by the amount of things we have to do, both at work and outside it. We leave work and have a bunch of emails, Facebook notifications, tweets, text messages (among others), waiting for response. Even worse, we are in bed keeping an eye open looking at our mobile phone in case we get a new notification. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/06/12/fashion/internet-technology-phones-introspection.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;This is ridiculous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/technology/2016/07/03/scaling-umbraco-on-windows-azure-II/</id>
        <title>Scaling Umbraco On Windows Azure Part II</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/technology/2016/07/03/scaling-umbraco-on-windows-azure-II/"/>
        <published>2016-07-03T13:02:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this second post of the three parts series about how to scale an Umbraco website on Windows Azure, we will install the CMS on our cloud platform.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;A one-click process, maybe a few more clicks&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t have one yet, create your &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/pricing/free-trial/&quot;&gt;Windows Azure Free Trial subscription&lt;/a&gt;, then log into your portal.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/03.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Create a new web site and install Umbraco.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/04.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/05.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Make sure you chose the right pricing for the database! For the demo, the free price tier is enough.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/06.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Configure the server.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/07.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Add the  App settings.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/08.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re all set up. Click create, your app is being deployed.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/09.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;After few minutes the deployment is complete.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/10.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;You can find the link to your website on the all resources link on the left hand side menu.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/11.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;The default app page will first appear, whilst the umbraco install is launching..
It should eventually prompt you for the login details you want to set up for the very first admin user of your umbraco installation.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/12.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Now is the time for you to grab a coffee and check your &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cats?lang=en-gb&quot;&gt;twitter feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/13.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;And here we are , ready to manage our website!
After a successful installation, we are taken to the admin page of our Umbraco CMS.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/14.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Ready to use layout template&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Since we installed the default template along with the Umbraco install, we have a starter kit, named Fanoe with layout template and site structure already built for us.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/15.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;We can study, in the admin of the website accessed via the &lt;code&gt;/umbraco path&lt;/code&gt; , the structure of our website.
We have a Homepage that is our Higher level page, and it contains &lt;code&gt;Learn, Explore and Extend&lt;/code&gt; as children items.
Each of those nodes are documents that are of a specific type and which are linked to a given template.
In our case, the Home document, is an instance of the Home Document Type and will be rendered through the Home Template.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/16.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;The Home Document Type (DT) is defined in the settings menu of the Umbraco website.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/17.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;The Home DT has two tabs defined, in the site tab we have a Site Description property of type Textarea, a Site Title property of type Textstring.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;The Home Template, is accessible under the Template folder of the Umbraco Settings menu.
It is nested under a master Template called &lt;code&gt;Master&lt;/code&gt; and it contains the code to display when the Home page is rendered.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/18.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Here the home page references a child template to display content from Grid data types.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/19.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Up and running in less than an hour : start adding pages&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;We have installed our Umbrao website and we are now familiar enough with how it works to be able to start adding content.
In the next part of this series, we will see how to scale our application on Windows Azure.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/technologies/2016/06/24/scaling-umbraco-on-windows-azure/</id>
        <title>Scaling an Umbraco Website On Windows Azure</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/technologies/2016/06/24/scaling-umbraco-on-windows-azure/"/>
        <published>2016-06-24T16:20:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first post of a three parts series about how to scale an Umbraco website on Windows Azure platform.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Part I: Yet another &lt;a href=&quot;https://umbraco.com/&quot;&gt;CMS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Umbraco is “The friendliest open source MVC .Net framework community”, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://our.umbraco.org/&quot;&gt;the Umbraco team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/umbraco/Umbraco-CMS&quot;&gt;open source content management system&lt;/a&gt; is built on the .Net MVC infrastructure, it allows developers to work on the business logic with Content and Media API, whilst front-end developers can focus on the rendering, look and feel of the website building views with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3schools.com/aspnet/webpages_razor.asp&quot;&gt;Razor markup&lt;/a&gt; and custom CSS.
Looking for an architecture representation of the Umbraco CMS, I have luckily found this diagram &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paulsterling/status/357223564019118080&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Sterling.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/01.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Modular and flexible, but not as blogger friendly as WordPress&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;It is very easy with Umbraco to build simple websites with custom objects and link them together, without writing any line of code. One can spin document types and add child document types in minutes.
Here is a simple diagram from @mcDark &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theoutfield.co.uk/blog/2011/04/anatomy-of-an-umbraco-document&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that explains how document types are structured.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/custom/blog/2016-06-20-umbraco-on-azure/02.png&quot;  alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img img-center img-responsive style-screengrab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;A Document Type in Umbraco is a concept that holds business logic, it is where one configure the properties one will need to store data. It can have a UI representation that is called a Template.
A Template is where the layout of how the data is displayed will be specified using HTML, Razor and CSS.
Blogging is not out of the box in Umbraco. There are however plugins that are called packages, to add blog functionality to Umbraco.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://our.umbraco.org/projects/starter-kits/articulate&quot;&gt;Articulate&lt;/a&gt; is the default blog package that comes installed with the starter kit.
It gives a good basic features sets to get starting blogging, however it does not provide some fundamental blog capabilities such as categories which need to be implemented using document types and require some workaround in the template.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Powerful indexing and built-in search capability&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Umbraco integrates &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shazwazza/Examine&quot;&gt;Examine&lt;/a&gt;, an indexing and search engine with two indexes already set up for internal search, helping you find your content on the admin of the website.
To improve usability of your website and help your visitors find your content, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://our.umbraco.org/documentation/reference/searching/examine/quick-start&quot;&gt;build your own indexes&lt;/a&gt; and search functionality.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;In this part we have been introduced to Umbraco, next we will see how easy it is to install and get up and running hosting our website on Windows Azure.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/software-craftsmanship/2016/06/22/Single-Responsibility-Principle/</id>
        <title>Some Thoughts on the Single Responsibility Principle</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/software-craftsmanship/2016/06/22/Single-Responsibility-Principle/"/>
        <published>2016-06-22T10:00:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1Da1b16&quot;&gt;SOLID&lt;/a&gt; (single responsibility, open-closed, Liskov substitution, interface segregation and dependency inversion) is a set of principles popularised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Cecil_Martin&quot;&gt;‘Uncle’ Bob Martin&lt;/a&gt; that aim to guide developers in implementing good software design. The principles define how Object Oriented classes should relate to each other in order to create a codebase that is flexible and able to accommodate ongoing change.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/software-craftsmanship/2016/06/17/thinking-in-abstractions/</id>
        <title>Thinking in Abstractions</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/software-craftsmanship/2016/06/17/thinking-in-abstractions/"/>
        <published>2016-06-17T00:20:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recent issues of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clojuregazette.com/archive.html&quot;&gt;Clojure Gazette&lt;/a&gt; have been discussing abstractions, and it&#39;s got me thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/practices/extreme-programming/2016/06/14/mastering-TDD/</id>
        <title>Mastering TDD</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/practices/extreme-programming/2016/06/14/mastering-TDD/"/>
        <published>2016-06-14T12:10:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I went to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paulstringer&quot;&gt;Paul Stringer&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; course &lt;a href=&quot;https://skillsmatter.com/courses/545-paul-stringer-s-mastering-tdd-bdd-for-ios&quot;&gt;&quot;Mastering TDD/BDD in iOS&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. After the two days, I was exhausted... During the course, we looked at all the theory, completed some exercises. Paul gave us lots of links and books to read and, quite frankly, I was feeling overwhelmed.
I saw myself in front of the computer, with all those links to follow and read, and I didn&#39;t know what to do... So I laid back on my chair and closed my eyes and thought... What do I know about TDD?&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2016/06/09/configuring-aws-for-lambda/</id>
        <title>Configuring Amazon Web Services (AWS) for using Lambda</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/2016/06/09/configuring-aws-for-lambda/"/>
        <published>2016-06-09T15:07:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;During the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://socratesuk.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Software Craftsmanship and Testing conference UK&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mashooq&quot;&gt;Mash&lt;/a&gt; run a session on &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/details/&quot;&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt;, with examples written in Java and python. Some other people also tried to do it in NodeJS. This session is &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/05/11/aws-lambdas&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/software-craftsmanship/2016/06/07/why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen/</id>
        <title>Why SoCraTes UK is not just a conference for Software Craftsmen.</title>
        <link href="http://codurance.com/software-craftsmanship/2016/06/07/why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen/"/>
        <published>2016-06-07T15:20:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Friday, I attended the international &lt;a href=&quot;http://socratesuk.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Software Craftsmanship and Testing conference&lt;/a&gt; at the enchanting Wotton House, in Dorking. I was the only Designer among about 100 Developers.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
</feed>
